<speak>
<break time="1200ms"/>
PC 12 Memory Items.
<break time="1200ms"/>

Airspeeds.
<break time="1200ms"/>
V, S, 0. 64 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, S, 1. 91 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, X. 110 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, Y. 120 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, glide at 9921 pounds. 114 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, glide at 6400 pounds. 93 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, A. Maneuvering speed at 9921 pounds. 158 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, A. Maneuvering speed at 5730 pounds. 120 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, R. 79 knots at flaps 15, 73 knots at flaps 30. <break time="800ms"/>
V, flaps at 15 degrees. 163 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, flaps at greater than 15 degrees. 130 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach at flaps 0. 118 knots. 134 knots in icing conditions. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach at flaps 15. 98 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach at flaps 30. 89 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach at flaps 40. 84 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach at flaps 15 and pusher Ice Mode. 108 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, approach in ice mode and boot failure. 130 knots on the series 10, 134 on the series 9. <break time="800ms"/>
V, N, E up to 15.2 thousand feet. 236 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, turbulence. 170 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, ice penetration. 140 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, holding. 140 to 170 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, L, O. 177 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
V, L, E. 236 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Max crosswind at flaps 0. 30 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Max crosswind at flaps 15. 25 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Max crosswind at flaps 30. 20 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Max crosswind at flaps 40. 15 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Weights.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Max ramp weight. 9965 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max Takeoff weight. 9921 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max landing weight. 9921 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max zero fuel weight. 9039 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max cargo weight. 3300 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max luggage weight. 400 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Aircraft System Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
De-ice boots temperature limits. Negative 40 to positive 40 celsius. <break time="800ms"/>
Outside air temperature range. Negative 55 celsius to positive 50 celsius. <break time="800ms"/>
One of the reasons for the Negative 55 Celsius minimum temperature is that it is the minimum temperature for proper operation of the fire detection loop. <break time="800ms"/>
Starting sequence limits. Sequence 1, 60 seconds off. Sequence 2, 60 seconds off. Sequence 3, 30 minutes off. <break time="800ms"/>
Autopilot altitude hold below 1000 feet AGL. Prohibited. <break time="800ms"/>
Ice on wing flap limitation. 15 degrees maximum. <break time="800ms"/>
Go around with ice on the airframe. Flaps remain at 15 degrees. <break time="800ms"/>
Prop De-ice modes. Mode 1, greater than 0 celsius, off. Mode 2, 0 to -16 celsius, 45 seconds per blade pair with 90 seconds of rest. Mode 3, less than -16 celsius, 90 seconds per blade pair with no rest. <break time="800ms"/>
Windshield Heat modes. Light heat, all three windshield sections on, drawing 28 amps. Heavy heat, only the center element on, drawing 26 amps. <break time="800ms"/>
Minimum altitude for use of the autopilot. 1000 feet for altitude hold, 200 feet in approach mode on an ILS with a functioning radar altimeter. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Engine Torque Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Max takeoff torque. 44.34 PSI for 5 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Max Transient torque. 61 PSI for 20 seconds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max continuous torque. 36.95 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Max reverse torque. 34.25 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Engine Temperature Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Max starting ITT. 1000 celsius. 870 to 1000 celsius for 5 seconds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max transient ITT. 870 celsius. 800 to 870 celsius for 20 seconds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max takeoff ITT. 800 celsius. 760 to 800 celsius for 5 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Max continuous ITT. 760 celsius. 720 celsius for cruise, 760 celsius for climb. <break time="800ms"/>
Max reverse ITT. 760 celsius. <break time="800ms"/>
Max idle ITT. 750 celsius. 50.7 to 61.4% N, G. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Engine Gas Generator Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Max takeoff, continuous and transient N.G., 104%. <break time="800ms"/>
Minimum idle N.G., 50% in ground idle, 64% in flight idle. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Engine Propellor Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Takeoff, continuous propeller RPM. 1700 RPM plus or minus 30 RPM. <break time="800ms"/>
Transient propeller RPM. Eighteen Seventy RPM for 20 seconds. <break time="800ms"/>
Max reverse propeller RPM. Sixteen Fifty RPM. <break time="800ms"/>
In the event of a Constant Speed Unit failure, the Overspeed governor will attempt to maintain. Eighteen Oh Two RPM. <break time="800ms"/>
In the event of a CSU and Overspeed governor failure, the Fuel topping governor will attempt to maintain. Eighteen Fifty Three RPM. <break time="800ms"/>
N.P. exceeding seventeen hundred is an indication of. Primary governor failure. <break time="800ms"/>
N.P. exceeding eighteen oh two is an indication of. Overspeed governor failure. <break time="800ms"/>
N.P. exceeding Eighteen Fifty Three is an indication of. N.F. or fuel topping governor failure. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Additional Engine Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Minimum oil pressure at idle. 60 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Maximum starting oil pressure. 200 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Transient oil pressure. 40 to 200 PSI limited to 20 seconds. <break time="800ms"/>
Takeoff, continuous, reverse oil pressure. 90 to 135 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Low oil pressure torque limit. 23.9 PSI max. <break time="800ms"/>
Starting oil temp. Minus 40 celsius minimum. <break time="800ms"/>
Idle, transient oil temp. Minus 40 celsius to 110 celsius, 105 to 110 celsius limited to 10 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Takeoff, continuous, reverse oil temperature. 10 to 105 celsius, 60 to 70 celsius recommended. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Electrical System Specifications.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Generator 1 specifications. 28 Volts, 300 Amps continuous capacity, 450 amps capacity for 2 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Generator 2 specifications. 28 volts, 115 amps. <break time="800ms"/>
Battery specifications. 24 volts, 40 amp hours for N,I, CAD and 42 amp hours for lead acid. <break time="800ms"/>
Single battery, no generator available duration. 60 amps for 20 minutes, 50 amps for 30 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Dual battery, no generator available duration. 60 amps for 40 minutes, 50 amps for 60 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Pressurization Limits.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Max cabin differential pressure. 5.75 PSI.  <break time="800ms"/>
Pressure relief valve open pressure. 6.35 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Pressurization system redline pressure. 6.5 PSI. <break time="800ms"/>
Cabin pressure CAWS. Illuminates at 10500 feet cabin pressure plus or minus 200 feet, or when 6.5 PSI cabin differential exceeded. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

Additional Aircraft Specifications.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Wingspan. 53 feet 3 inches on the series 9, and 53 feet and 4 inches on the series 10.  <break time="800ms"/>
Height. 14 feet.  <break time="800ms"/>
Length. 47 feet 3 inches.  <break time="800ms"/>
Engine. PT6A-67B.  <break time="800ms"/>
Total fuel capacity. 406.8 gallons or 2736.5 pounds.  <break time="800ms"/>
Usable fuel capacity. 402 gallons or 2703.6 pounds.  <break time="800ms"/>
Unusable fuel. 4.8 Gallons.  <break time="800ms"/>
Collector tank capacity. 20 Gallons.  <break time="800ms"/>
Max fuel imbalance. 3 fuel segments, 26.4 gallons or 178 pounds. <break time="800ms"/>
Fuel low CAWS. Illuminates when there is less than 20 gallons in the tank. <break time="800ms"/>
Engine oil type in use. Eastman turbo oil twenty three eighty. <break time="800ms"/>
Oil capacity. 3.6 Gallons. <break time="800ms"/>
Oil drain and refill quantity. 2 gallons. <break time="800ms"/>
Oil quantity operating range. 1 gallon. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="2s"/>

</speak>
