<speak>
Regulations and policy
<break time="1200ms"/>

When do you not need an alternate for your destination?
<break time="1200ms"/>
For one hour before or after the expected time of arrival, the ceiling must be at least 1,500 feet above the lowest circling approach Minimum Descent Altitude, or <break time="300ms"/>
If a circling instrument approach procedure is not authorized, the ceiling must be at least 1,500 feet above the lowest ceiling minimums or 2,000 feet above airport elevation, whichever is higher, and <break time="300ms"/>
The visibility must be forecast to be at least 3 statute miles, or 2 statute miles more than the lowest applicable visibility minimums, whichever is greater, for the instrument approach procedure to be used at the destination airport.
<break time="1200ms"/>

Alternate Airport IFR Weather Minimums.
<break time="1200ms"/>
For airports with at least one navigation facility, add 400 feet to the minimum descent altitude or decision altitude and 1 statute mile to the visibility. For airports with at least two navigation facilities and straight-in approaches to at least two different runways, add 200' to the minimum descent altitude or decision altitude and half of a statute mile to the visibility.
<break time="1200ms"/>

IFR takeoff minimums
<break time="1200ms"/>
Standard takeoff minimums for aircraft with 2 or less engines is 1 statute mile. If minimums are standard for the airport, then you can use the lowest CAT 1 minimum for the airport. Touchdown zone RVR <break time="300ms"/>(if reported) <break time="300ms"/> is controlling for the minimum visibilities. If the airport has a nonstandard takeoff minimum that are greater than standard, then the nonstandard minimum supersedes all others.
<break time="1200ms"/>

When is takeoff alternate required?
<break time="1200ms"/>
If the visibility is lower than the lowest approach minimums then you must have an alternate for your departure.
<break time="1200ms"/>

Lost communication procedures.
<break time="1200ms"/>
Transponder set to 7600. <break time="800ms"/>
Route, <break time="300ms"/>Cleared, <break time="300ms"/>Expected, <break time="300ms"/>Filed. <break time="800ms"/>
Altitude, highest of <break time="300ms"/>Assigned, <break time="300ms"/>Minimum enroute, <break time="300ms"/>expected altitude.
<break time="1200ms"/>

Land and hold short restrictions.
<break time="1200ms"/>
- Landing distance should be A.F.M. plus 1000 feet. <break time="800ms"/>
- No wet runways. <break time="800ms"/>
- The runway must have electronic or visual approach guidance. <break time="800ms"/>
- Weather of no less than a 1500 foot ceiling, and a visibility of no less than 5 statute miles. <break time="800ms"/>
- Weather can be reduced to 1000 and 3 if a PAPI or VASI is installed and operational. <break time="800ms"/>
- Where a rejected landing procedure is published, weather minima will be published in local flying directives. <break time="800ms"/>
- LAH SO is not authorized if wind shear is reported in the 20 minutes prior to the LAH SO clearance. <break time="800ms"/>
- Tailwind should be calm or less than 3 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
- Night LAH SO only with approved LAH SO lighting installed. <break time="800ms"/>
- Reference, Op spec Alpha Oh 2 7. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="1200ms"/>

<break time="1200ms"/>
Requirements for descending below the Decision or minimum descent altitudes. You need to have any of the following in sight.
<break time="300ms"/>the runway or environment.
<break time="300ms"/>the approach lighting system.
<break time="300ms"/>the threshold marking or lighting.
<break time="300ms"/>the runway end identifier lights.
<break time="300ms"/>the VASI.
<break time="300ms"/>the touchdown zone markings or lights.
<break time="300ms"/> and the runway markings or lights. Additionally, you need the required flight visibility and can make a normal approach and landing.

<break time="1200ms"/>
Speed limit below 10000 feet. 250 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Speed limit below class Bravo airspace or a VFR corridor. 200 knots. <break time="800ms"/>
Speed limit for class Charlie or Delta. 200 knots within 4 nautical miles and up to 2500 A. G. L. <break time="800ms"/>
Rest requirements. 10 hours of rest within the preceding 24 hours to the start of duty. <break time="800ms"/>

<break time="1200ms"/>
Flight hour limits.
<break time="300ms"/>8 hours per day,
<break time="300ms"/>500 hours per quarter,
<break time="300ms"/>800 hours every 2 consecutive quarters,
<break time="300ms"/>1400 hours per calendar year.
<break time="300ms"/>Reference, one thirty five, two sixty seven.

<break time="1200ms"/>
Documents required.
<break time="300ms"/>Airworthiness certificate,
<break time="300ms"/>Aircraft registration,
<break time="300ms"/>Radio station licence for flights outside of the US,
<break time="300ms"/>Operating limitations,
<break time="300ms"/>weight and balance data,
<break time="300ms"/>avionics manuals,
<break time="300ms"/>company issued electronic flight bag,
<break time="300ms"/>aircraft maintenance logbook.
<break time="1200s"/>

One Thirthy Five Oxygen Requirements
<break time="1200ms"/>
For pilots. <break time="300ms"/>
At MSL altitudes or cabin altitudes above 10000 through 12000 feet. Continuously after 30 minutes. <break time="800ms"/>
Above 12000. Continuously. <break time="800ms"/>
For passengers. <break time="300ms"/>
At MSL altitudes or cabin altitudes above 10000 through 15000 feet. Available to supply at least 10% of passengers after 30 minutes at those altitudes. <break time="800ms"/>
Above 15000 feet. Supplied to all passengers. <break time="800ms"/>
Above 25000 feet in pressurized aircraft. At least a 10 minute supply to all occupants of the aircraft, for use in the event of the loss of cabin pressurization.
<break time="1000ms"/>
Reference one thirty five, eighty nine and one fifty seven.
<break time="1200ms"/>

One thirty five V.F.R. minimums
<break time="1200ms"/>
VFR minimum altitudes. <break time="1000ms"/>
Daytime, 500 feet above the surface and 500 feet horizontally from any obstacle. <break time="800ms"/>
At night, 1000 feet above the highest obstacle within 5 miles of the course to be flown or 2000 feet in mountainous terrain. <break time="1000ms"/>
VFR minimum visibility. <break time="1000ms"/>
In uncontrolled airspace, not less than 1000 feet ceilings unless the flight visibility is at least 2 miles.
<break time="800ms"/> Reference one thirty five two zero three and two zero five.
<break time="1200ms"/>

M.E.L. category durations
<break time="1200ms"/>
Category A. Defined in M.E.L. <break time="800ms"/>
Category B. 3 days. <break time="800ms"/>
Category C. 10 days. <break time="800ms"/>
Category D. 120 days. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="1200ms"/>

Medical certificate duration. First Class, 12 calendar months if under 40 and 6 months if 40 or older. Second class, 12 calendar months. Third class, 60 calendar months if under 40 and 24 calendar months if 40 or older. <break time="800ms"/>
Pre-takeoff contamination check. Pre-takeoff contamination check must be done within 5 minutes of takeoff. <break time="800ms"/>
Continuing an approach at the destination. Must have the required minimums to continue unless past the final approach fix on the approach. <break time="800ms"/>
Width of a victor airway. 8 nautical miles, 4 miles on either side of the center. <break time="800ms"/>
Standard holding pattern turning direction. To the right. <break time="800ms"/>
Information to report to ATC upon entering a hold. Time and altitude reaching the clearance limit. Begin slowing to holding speed within 3 minutes or less. <break time="800ms"/>
3 degree Glideslope calculation. Half of your ground speed multiplied by 10. <break time="800ms"/>
</speak>
