<speak>
Opspec Review
<break time="1200ms"/>

Alpha One. Primary Business Address. Doing business as names. Authorization to operate under part 91. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha two. Definitions and abbreviations. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha three. Authorized aircraft types. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha four. List of authorized opspec paragraphs. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha six. List of management personel. <break time="300ms"/>
Chief Pilot, Nathan Larson-Alexander. <break time="300ms"/>
Director of Operations, Nicholas Cusimano. <break time="300ms"/>
Director of Quality Assurance, Steven Sobezak. <break time="300ms"/>
Director of Maintenance, George Tanos. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha seven. List of designated persons. <break time="300ms"/>
Agent for service, Jeremy Salveson. <break time="300ms"/>
The Chief Pilot, Director of Maintenance, Director of Operations and director of quality assurance can apply for and recive op specs. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha eight. List of persons with operational control. Consist of the Director of Operations, the Chief Pilot and the Director of Maintenance. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha nine. Defines the means by which the certificate holder will obtain, maintain, and distribute aeronautical data for the airports it uses. Located in G.O.M chapter 5<break time="800ms"/>
Alpha ten. Approved sources of aviation weather information. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha fifteen. Authorization to use an autopilot in lieu of a second in command along with a list of approved autopilot systems. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha twenty four. Authorization to perform air ambulance operations.
Alpha twenty five. Authorization to use electronic signatures, electronic record keeping systems and electronic manual systems along with a list of approved systems.
Alpha twenty seven. Authorization to perform Land and Hold Short Operations. <break time="300ms"/>
Landing distance should be AFM plus 1000 feet. <break time="300ms"/>
No wet runways. <break time="300ms"/>
Runway must have electronic or visual approach guidance. <break time="300ms"/>
Weather of no less than a 1500 foot ceiling and a visibility of no less than 5 statute miles. <break time="300ms"/>
Weather can be reduced to 1000 and 3 if a PAPI or VASI is installed and operational. <break time="300ms"/>
Where a rejected landing procedure is published, weather minima will be published in local flying directives. <break time="300ms"/>
LAH SO not authorized if windshear reported in the 20 minutes prior to the LAH SO clearance. <break time="300ms"/>
Tailwind should be calm or less than 3 knots. <break time="300ms"/>
Night LAH SO only with approved LAH SO lighting installed. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha thirty one. Authorization to use contract training facilities. <break time="800ms"/>
Alpha forty one. Authorization to complete a pre-takeoff contamination check. <break time="800ms"/>
<break time="1200ms"/>


</speak>
